The class library that's a
part of the JDK includes a
rich set of classes designed
for network communications.
Among the tasks that they
support, they give you the
ability to easily retrieve
and read files over the web.
I'll show you one approach to
doing this using the classes
of the Java class library.
I'll mention before I get
started that there are easier
ways that require less code
if you use the Apache Commons
library, but it's good to
know what's available in the
core class library first.
I'm working in a project
called Network Files, and a
class called ReadNetworkFile,
and I'm working with
an empty main method.
The first step in
getting a network file
is knowing its location.
You should wrap the location
in the file in an instance
of a class named URL, for
Uniform Resource Locator.
I'll type in the name of the
class, which is all uppercase,
and I'll press Control
Space, and choose the version
in the package java.net.
I'll name that variable
URL, all lowercase.